Tadeu Garcia

Senior Product Designer

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Summary

Experienced designer with creating digital products for B2B and B2C SaaS, E-commerce, Marketplaces, Billing and Payment Systems, Back-office applications. Skilled in web components and Material Design for desktop and mobile.

linkedin.com/in/garciatadeu (LinkedIn) tadeugarcia.com (Portfolio) tadeugarcia.92@gmail.com (Email) +55 21 979976655 (Mobile)

Brazilian, obtaining Spanish citizenship by end-2024.

Work Experience

+A Educação

Senior Product Designer

November 2022 - Present Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

I contribute to the student billing system, from designing payment screens to managing payments in the back-office.

I was involved in a comprehensive redesign of the health courses marketplace, covering everything from product discovery to delivery. My role spanned from initial wireframing to usability testing and planning post-launch future enhancements, until this product reaches maturity in its lifecycle.

Main activities:

 Experimentation for continuous product evolution with A/B testing, user interviews, usability testing, surveys, quantitative and qualitative data analysis.

- User research and documentation of processes and results.
- Creating low to high-fidelity interactive prototypes for desktop and mobile, using design system components.
- Creating and maintenance of Design System components.
- Defining OKRs/KPIs metrics, personas, and journey mapping with the product manager.
- Communication with developers, testers, product owners, and product managers in agile teams using scrum.
- People management and training.

+A Educação

Product Designer

January 2021 - November 2022 Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

Informal Serviços e Consultoria em Informática

Lead UI/UX Engineer

September 2018 - December 2020 Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

I was involved in designing app screens and flows from conception to publishing on app stores, following Material Design guidelines.

I participated in a major project with the Brazilian Federation of Banks, involving a complex refund and payment system to reimburse fiscal credits seized in previous decades.

I worked on creating data analytics interfaces, that displayed financial and order summary data for large Brazilian retail companies.

Main activities:

- Creating low to high-fidelity interactive prototypes and delivering production-ready front-end code to back-end developers.
- Creating data analytics interfaces through dashboards, KPIs, and graphs.
- People management and training.

Informal Serviços e Consultoria em Informática

UI/UX Engineer

December 2016 - September 2018

Noblinddz

Art Director

April 2015 - December 2016 Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Main activities:

- Creating low to high-fidelity interactive prototypes for institutional websites and landing pages.
- Creation of banners, email marketing, social media posts, and presentations.

Agência h1

Junior Art Director

September 2014 - April 2015 Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Main activities:

- · Designing institutional websites and landing pages.
- Creation of static and animated banners, email marketing, social media posts, and video editing.

Agência h1

Intern Art Director

September 2013 - September 2014 Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Obra Social Dona Meca

Intern Graphic Designer

April 2013 - September 2013 Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Main activities:

• Creation of social media posts, posters and other printed materials.

Education

Postgraduate's degree

Ergodesign of Interfaces: Usability and Information Architecture (2016)

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Associate's degree

Graphic Design (2014)

Universidade Estácio de Sá

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Skills

- Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Upper Intermediate B2 level)
- UI/UX Design: Prototyping (desktop and mobile, low to high-fidelity), Design Systems, Web Components, Material Design, UX Patterns, UI Patterns
- Design Tools: Figma (Auto Layout, Components, Variants), Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Axure,
 Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere)
- UX Research: User Research, User Interviews, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Surveys, Journey Mapping, Recruitment, UX Metrics, Data Analysis
- Data & Analytics: Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Google Optimize, Hotjar, Clarity, Maze
- Front-end Development: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, WordPress, Zeplin
- Version Control & Development Tools: Git, NPM, Chrome DevTools
- Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Kanban
 Collaboration Tools: Microsoft Office Suite, Google Docs, FigJam, Miro, Mural, HubSpot
- · Accessibility: WCAG Guidelines, Accessibility testing, Screen reader testing